# **Bala Ganapathy Parthiban**



# Full-Stack Software Engineer

balaganapathy.parthiba@gmail.com



📞 (+91)8667233744 🕝 balaganapathy.dev 🎧 github/balaganapathyparthiban

# **Objective**

A self-motivated software engineer with 4+ years of experience and considerable technical skill who possesses self-discipline and ability to work with minimum of supervision. Able to play a key role in web app development to ensure maximum accessibility, user experience and usability. A quick learner who can absorb new ideas and can communicate clearly and effectively.

## Education

Sree Sastha Institute of Engineering & Technology 2013 - 2017 // Chennai, Tamilnadu, India Bachelor of Engineering in Electronic and Communication.

# Relevant Experience

Senior System Engineer @ Infosys Pvt Ltd Jun 2020 - Present // Chennai, Tamilnadu, India

- ► Worked as part of an agile team to write modern, performant, and robust code to develop interactive web applications for a client BASF Pvt Ltd.
- ► Written an AWS lambda functions to calculate the weather data and to plot complex Graphs and Charts in Front end application.
- ► Works with various technologies such as React, Angular, Spring boot, Go Fiber, PostgreSQL, AWS, Azure etc.
- ► Tested sites in various browsers and devices to ensure cross-browser compatibility and mobile responsiveness.
- ► Communicate and collaborate with multi-disciplinary teams of engineers, designers, producers, clients, and stakeholders on a daily basis.

Software Developer @ Casperon technologies Pvt Ltd Oct 2018 - May 2020 // Chennai, Tamilnadu, India

- Worked with a team to build an on-demand and e-commerce web application for a diverse array of clients and internal projects.
- Work with various languages and frameworks such as React, Angular, css/scss, Nodejs, Python, MongoDB, Elastic search etc.
- Interacting with clients on a weekly basis and providing project oriented technological expertise and knowledge.

# Open Source Projects

Easy Scrum // easyscrum.balaganapathy.dev

Web app built with React & Gun.js Decentralised database for Agile teams to estimate, prioritise product backlog & conduct retrospectives.

Quickshare // quickshare.balaganapathy.dev

File sharing in Quickshare is guick and easy by just sharing a link, you can send anything from photos, videos and zipped folders also can set and password for files, Web app was built with React, Go and Fiber.

Cloudbox // cloudbox.balaganapathy.dev

Cloudbox is an open source decentralised application able to securely store files, images, videos, audios and notes. Build with React, Web3.storage and Gun.js.

## Skills

## **Programming Languages**

- Javascript(ES6)
- Typescript
- ► HTML & CSS/SCSS
- ► Python
- ► Go
- ▶ Rust
- ▶ Java

### Libraries & Frameworks

- ► Reactis
- ► Angular 2+
- Node.js, Express.js
- Sprintboot
- Flask
- Go Fiber
- GraphQL
- ► Web Socket & WebRTC

#### **Database**

- ► MongoDB
- PostgreSQL
- ► Neo4i
- Redis
- ► Elastic search

## Tools & Platforms

- ► Git
- AWS
- Azure
- Firebase
- Docker & Docker Swarm
- Kubernetes

# Learning & Certification

- Microservices with Node JS and React (udemy)
- Building Modern Web Application with Go (udemy)
- Master Python programming by solving scientific projects (udemy)
- Docket Mastery with Kubernetes + Swam from Docker Captain (udemy)
- Machine Learning A-Z Hands on Python & R in Data Science (udemy)